# RIDWAN ABDULSALAM

# FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (MERN)



+234 812 439 6303

riliwanademola@yahoo.com



Lagos Nigeria

#### **PROFILE**

A Dedicated and efficient Fullstack Devloper with experience in frontend development and backend development to develop fully functioning web application and also creating a stellar finished product with MERN (MongoDB, Express, Reactis, Node) stack.

Frontend: I am responsible in building Responsive and User-friendly dynamic Frontend User interface and also Optimizing

Backend: My goal as a backend developer is the ability to Oversea the overall architecture and infrastructure of a system, Design secured Servers/Database and also involve in API development and Administration.

I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements. This has allowed me to stay ahead of curve and deliver exceptional work to all my client.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS



HTML5 Advanced



CSS3 Advanced



**Typescript** Intermediate



ReactJS Advanced



Redux Advanced NextJS NextJS Advanced



Sass Advanced



Adeolu Senior Secondary school

2006 - 2012

Senior Secondary Certificate of Education





MongoDB Intermediate

#### **EDUCATION**

Higher National Diploma - Computer Science

CGPA: 3.33 / 4.00

Yaba College of Technology

2017 - 2019

National Diploma - Computer Science

CGPA: 3.45 / 4.00

Yaba College of Technology

2014 - 2017

### PROJECT AND ACTIVITIES

Final year project-Online Car Rentals And Driver Hiring System

- · Gathered project requirements and specifications.
- · Learnt alot about Internet of Things.
- · Designed and developed the parts user interface .

## SOFT SKILLS

Desire and willingness to learn Excellent communication skills Giving clear feedback Facilitating others

Great attention to detail Highly organized Willing to accept feedback

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### OBIG TECHNOLOGIES - Frontend Developer(Intern)

August 2020 - Present

Shopabox

Shopabox is an online Shopping / Retail platform that gives users best shopping experience and it a product of Obig Technologies.

I designed part of the design system and the Landing-page of Shopabox [shopabox-www.vercel.app].

SPOTTR - Frontend Developer

Contract (April 2022 - May 2022)

	SpottR  The SpottR app projects to connect millions of households and businesses in Africa with seamless economic opportunity spotlighting and matching. SpottR uses powerful modern-day technology - geolocation and AI - to help users find other users, businesses, goods, services, events, jobs and anything of value (opportunities) that can be transacted. The SpottR oracle crunches data from its ecosystem and makes it available for businesses to utilize the same for business optimization. I redesigned the UI of SpottR web app [spottr.app].		
LANGUAGES	English	Yoruba	Pidgin
	Proficient	Native	Aiternative

Github Profile: Sirlahm

in Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ridwan-abdulsalam-81bba01b1">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ridwan-abdulsalam-81bba01b1</a>

Portfolio: ridwanabdulsalam.netlify.app